Guide to the Frederick R. Koch Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Alphabetical Name List
  - Liszt, Franz
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - [Liszt?], Eduard (uncle), 1872 Nov 6 (Box 26, Folder 569)
        FRKF 1129
      - Liszt, Eduard (cousin), 1857-64 (Box 26, Folder 570)
        FRKF 1056
        FRKF 1057
        FRKF 1058
      - Lynen, Marie, 1882, 1886 (Box 26, Folder 571)
        FRKF 477.1-2
      - Reinecke, Carl, 1849 May 30 (Box 26, Folder 572)
        FRKF 817
      - Sampieri, Francesco, 1839 Jan 14 (Box 26, Folder 573)
        FRKF 768
      - Unidentified, 1828 Apr 1 (Box 26, Folder 574)
        FRKF 564
    - MUSIC
      - Ballade, piano, no. 1, D-flat major
        - Early version: draft of music for piano (Box 26, Folder 575)
          FRKF 1305
      - Freischütz Fantasie (piano)
        - Fragment of music for piano, [ca. 1840]
          FRKF 1033
      - Für Männergesang, no. 4
        See: Trost I (chorus, male voices), box 325, folder 1782
      - Für Männergesang, no. 5
      - Grosses Konzertsolo (piano)
        Fragment of music for piano
        FRKF 816
      - Ich möchte hingehn (song)
        - Incomplete score, n.d.
          Accompanied by an engraved portrait of Liszt
          FRKF 385
      - Nicht gezagt (chorus, male voices)
      - O du mein holder Abendstern (piano)
        Transcription of Wagner, Richard, Tannhäuser. O du mein holder Abendstern
        - Proof of music for piano (Paris: J. Meissonnier Fils), [ca. 1849]
          FRKF 1037
      - Réminiscences de La juive (piano)
        - Fragment of music for piano, n.d.
          FRKF 769
      - Resignazione (piano)
        - Draft of music for piano, 1877 Oct 25
          FRKF 1146
      - Seconde marche hongroise (piano)
        - Revised version: music for piano, 1875 Oct 14
          FRKF 709
      - Trost I (chorus, male voices)
        - Second version ( Für Männergesang, no. 4 ): score, [1860]
          Also includes Nicht gezagt, second version ( Für Männergesang, no. 5 ), score
          FRKF 855
    - OTHER PAPERS
      - Caricature of Liszt: in pencil, [late 19th c?] (Box 26, Folder 576)
        FRKF 770
  - Loos, Anita
    All materials, unless otherwise indicated: FRKF 1431
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Barillet, Pierre, 1952-77, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 577-579)
        Includes postcards also signed by Jean-Pierre Grédy
      - Beaton, Cecil, 1948-68, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 580)
      - Bemelmans, Ludwig, 1954-57, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 581)
        Includes letter from Bemelmans to Charles MacArthur Includes drafts relating to Daisy by Loos, Bemelmans, and Charles MacArthur
      - Gordon, Ruth
        See: Grédy, Jean-Pierre, box 26, folder 582
      - Grédy, Jean-Pierre, 1951-76, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 582)
        Includes postcard also signed by Ruth Gordon, Garson Kanin, Maria Mauban, and unidentified
        See also: Barillet, Pierre, box 26, folder 577-579
      - Howell, Miriam, 1966 Mar 10 (Box 26, Folder 583)
        Written by a secretary
      - Huxley, Aldous, 1926-57, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 584)
        FRKF 192
      - Johnson, Nunnally, 1956 Oct 20 (Box 26, Folder 585)
      - Kanin, Garson
      - Mauban, Maria
        See: Grédy, Jean-Pierre. box 26, folder 582
      - Mizner, Addison, 1928 Mar 7 (Box 26, Folder 586)
      - Mizner, Wilson, 1927-32, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 587)
      - Unidentified, 1953 Dec 30 (Box 26, Folder 588)
        See also: Grédy, Jean-Pierre, box 26, folder 582
    - WRITINGS
      - Biography of Wilson Mizner
        - Proposal, typescript, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 589)
        - Background materials, typescript and clippings, 1932-42, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 590)
        - Draft fragments, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 591)
      - Daisy (play)
        - Drafts, typescript, corrected, 1956, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 592-597)
        - Act I: drafts, typescript, some corrected, 1960, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 598-602)
        - Act II: draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 603)
        - Fragments, typescript, some corrected, 1959, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 604-610)
      - Other writings
        - Unidentified, 1953, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 611-612)
          See also: Correspondence/Bemelmans, Ludwig, box 26, folder 581
    - OTHER PAPERS
      - Bemelmans, Ludwig. "Adieu to the Ritz," proof, n.d.
      - Photograph of Loos with Pierre Barillet, Natalie Paley, and Clifton Webb (Box 28, Folder 613)
  - Loti, Pierre
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Hahn, Reynaldo, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 614)
        FRKF 658.7
      - Montebello, Marquise de, [ca. 1891] (Box 28, Folder 615)
        FRKF 65
  - Louis Napoléon, Prince Impérial of the French
  - Louis Philippe, King of the French
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Lannes, Napoléon, duc de Montebello, 1847 Feb-Jul (Box 28, Folder 616)
        FRKF 66
        FRKF 321
  - Louise-Marie, of Orléans, Queen
    Full name: Louise-Marie, of Orléans, Queen, consort of Léopold I, King of the Belgians
    - WRITINGS
      - Diary, 1850 May-Sep (Box 28, Folder 617)
        Accompanied by blank envelopes, a pressed plant, and a printed calendar
        FRKF 1293
  - Louÿs, Pierre
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      See also: Music/Unidentified/Parodies, sketches, and fragments, box 28, folder 620
      See also: Music/Unidentified/Parodies, sketches, and fragments, box 326, folder 1786
      - Debussy, Claude, [1894-99], n.d. (Box 28, Folder 618)
        Includes letter in the form of music for two voices and piano
        FRKF 244
        FRKF 244.5
        FRKF 251
      - Unidentified, [1901 Feb 7] (Box 28, Folder 619)
        FRKF 727
    - MUSIC
      See also: Correspondence/Debussy, Claude, box 28, folder 618
      - Chanson des rois mages
        Score in the hand of Claude Debussy
        FRKF 499
      - Unidentified
        - Parodies, sketches, and fragments (Box 28, Folder 620)
          Includes: Parodies of Georges Bizet and Richard Strauss Drawing and notes Envelope addressed to Louÿs from Mustel, père & fils
          FRKF 499.5
    - WRITINGS
      - Le livre des eaux et de la nuit (poems): drafts and printed clippings, 1889-1901, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 621)
        Accompanied by a description and certification of authenticity, by a former owner
        FRKF 1365
  - Ludwig I, King of Bavaria
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Zimmermann, Clemens von, 1859 Dec 29 (Box 28, Folder 622)
        FRKF 830
  - Ludwig II, King of Bavaria
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Bülow, Hans von, 1869 Feb 26 (Box 28, Folder 623)
        FRKF 77
      - Holstein, Count von, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 624)
        FRKF 78
      - Quaglia, Angelo, Cardinal, 1866 Jan 31 (Box 28, Folder 625)
        In a secretarial hand
        FRKF 76
  - Maeterlinck, Maurice
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - [Harden, Maximilian?], [1891?] (Box 29, Folder 626)
        FRKF 1371
      - Unidentified, 1902-04, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 627)
        FRKF 535c
        FRKF 801
  - Mahler, Gustav
    - MUSIC
      - Lieder und Gesänge aus der Jugendzeit
        - Selbstgefühl: score in the hand of F. Weidig, with annotations by Mahler
          FRKF 330
        - Starke Einbildungskraft: score in the hand of F. Weidig, with annotations by Mahler
          FRKF 329
  - Malibran, Maria
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Rothschild, baroness de, 1830 Mar 26 (Box 29, Folder 628)
        FRKF 682
      - Sampieri, Francesco, [1834] Apr 24 (Box 29, Folder 629)
        FRKF 757
    - MUSIC
      - Le matelot (song)
        - Score, possibly in holograph, n.d.
          FRKF 1034
  - Mascagni, Pietro
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Mascagni, Lina, 1893, 1895 (Box 29, Folder 630)
        FRKF 439
        FRKF 440
      - Mascagni, Maria, 1889-90 (Box 29, Folder 631)
        FRKF 1340
      - Mascagni, Mario, 1919-38, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 632-633)
        FRKF 1343
        FRKF 1345
      - Rossi, Renzo, 1932 Mar 19 (Box 29, Folder 634)
        FRKF 1341.1
    - MUSIC
      - Alla gioia (cantata)
        - Incomplete short score, 1881-82
          FRKF 538
      - Canzone popolare (flute, violin, violoncello, and piano)
        - Score, 1882 Jun 1
          FRKF 1332
      - In filanda (cantata)
        - Short score, with printed program for first performances, 1880-81
          FRKF 1036
      - Inno ad Adelaide Cairoli (song)
        - Score, 1898 Dec 3
          FRKF 1143
      - Invocazione alla madonna (chorus and orchestra)
        - Version for chorus and organ: score and fragment, 1932 Aug 6
          FRKF 1344
      - Isabeau (opera)
        - Notes about the libretto, n.d.
          FRKF 793.1
      - Nerone (opera)
        - Score, 1933-34
          FRKF 2
      - Pinotta (opera)
        - Excerpt titled "Coro di Filatrici": score, 1884 Jun
          FRKF 1339
      - Sì (opera)
        - Fragments, partly in holograph, 1919 Sep 10-29
          FRKF 362a
    - OTHER PAPERS
      - Photographs of Pietro and Lina Mascagni, 1890, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 635)
        FRKF 1342.1
  - Massenet, Jules
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Claretie, Jules, [1911 Jun 15] (Box 29, Folder 636)
        FRKF 539a
      - Manuel, [Eugène?], 1877 May 2 (Box 29, Folder 637)
        FRKF 20.5
      - Marchesi, Mathilde, 1888 Feb 9 (Box 29, Folder 638)
        FRKF 710
      - Mirbeau, Octave, 1891 Jul 22 (Box 29, Folder 639)
        FRKF 662a
      - Viardot-García, Pauline, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 640)
        FRKF 721.1
      - Unidentified, 1873-1912, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 641)
        FRKF 721.2-4
        FRKF 928
        FRKF 1335
    - MUSIC
      - Amadis (opera)
        - Libretto, [1910?]
      - Ariane (opera)
        See: Thérèse (opera)/Original folders, box 326, folder 1799
      - Le bac (piano), 1879 Aug 13
        Music for piano
        FRKF 91
      - Bacchus (opera)
        - Draft without vocal parts, [1908]
          FRKF 904
      - Chanson pour elle
        - Orchestral version: score, partly in holograph, [1897 or later]
          FRKF 844
      - Cléopâtre (opera)
        - Draft without vocal parts, [ca. 1912]
          FRKF 912
      - Don Quichotte (opera)
        See: Roma (opera), box 141, folder 1483
      - Les Erinnyes (incidental music)
        - Score, [1872-76]
          FRKF 910
      - Eve (oratorio)
        - Score, 1874 Nov 1
          FRKF 907
      - Fantaisie, violoncello, orchestra, D major
        - Version for violoncello and piano: score, 1896-97
          FRKF 705
      - Hérodiade (opera)
        - Original version: short score, 1879-80
          FRKF 544
      - Jérusalem (incidental music)
        - Short and full scores, [1912]
          FRKF 894
          FRKF 894.5
      - Marche solennelle (orchestra)
        - Score, 1881
          FRKF 909
      - Mienne! (song)
        - Score, 1893 Aug 25
          FRKF 703
      - Panurge (opera)
        - Draft without vocal parts, [ca. 1912]
          FRKF 903
      - Roma (opera)
        - Draft without vocal parts, [ca. 1909-10]
          Includes drafts for Don Quichotte (opera) and unidentified works
          FRKF 895
      - Scènes alsaciennes (orchestra)
        - Score, with fragment from original binding, 1881
          FRKF 902
      - Scènes hongroises (orchestra)
        - Score, 1871-75
          FRKF 893
      - Scènes napolitaines (orchestra)
        - Score, 1878 Jun 22
          FRKF 911
      - Soir de printemps (melodrama, voice and piano)
        - Score, 1893 Dec 21
          FRKF 704
      - Suite parnassienne (solo voices, chorus, and orchestra)
        - Draft without vocal parts, [1912?]
          FRKF 906
      - Suite théâtrale (solo voice and orchestra)
        - Draft without vocal part, and incomplete short and full scores
          FRKF 908
          FRKF 908.05
      - La terre promise (oratorio)
        - Score, 1897-99
          FRKF 896
      - Thérèse (opera)
        - Draft without vocal parts, [ca. 1907]
          FRKF 905
        - Original folders, [ca. 1907]
          Includes annotations relating to Ariane (opera)
      - La Vierge (oratorio)
        - Score, with fragments from original bindings, 1878-80
          FRKF 897
      - Unidentified
        See also: Roma, box 141, folder 1483
        - Fragment, possibly from an orchestral work, n.d.
          FRKF 20
    - WRITINGS
      - "La fille de Jephté" (libretto): synopsis, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 642)
        With correspondence of a former owner, 1946 May-Aug
        FRKF 501
  - Maugham, Robin
    Papers relate to W. Somerset Maugham, the Maugham family, and Robin Maugham's Somerset and All the Maughams
    - WRITINGS
      - Diaries
        Accompanied by typed transcripts
        All materials: FRKF 191a, FRKF 191e
        - Diaries, 1956, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 643)
        - Diaries, 1961-64 (Box 29, Folder 644-651)
        - Diaries, 1965-66 (Box 30, Folder 652-655)
      - Somerset and All the Maughams
        See also: Research Files, boxes 31-37, folders 671-754
        See also: Research Files, boxes 327, folders 1801-1803
        - Background materials (Box 30, Folder 656-661)
          FRKF 191b
        - Drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 31, Folder 662-670)
          Includes correspondence
          FRKF 191k
          FRKF 191p
    - RESEARCH FILES
      See also: Writings/ Somerset and All the Maughams, boxes 30-31, folders 656-670
      See also: Maugham Family Papers, boxes 37-39, folders 755-791
      See also: Maugham Family Papers, box 82, folder 1424
      See also: Maugham Family Papers, box 327, folder 1805-1806
      See also: Maugham Family Papers, Bsd, folder 2083
      All materials: FRKF 191b, FRKF 191d, FRKF 191i, FRKF 191l
      - "Family Book (Misc.)"
        - Correspondence, 1963-64, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 671)
        - Notes and other papers, 1963-64, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 672)
      - "Family File"
        Note on original box: "To be sorted when family book is published"
        - Maugham, Mabel ("Beldy"), 1962-63, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 673)
        - Maugham, Robert Ormond, 1883-1963, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 674-675)
        - Maugham, W. Somerset (biography), 1946-63, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 676-677)
        - Maugham family (Bath, Germany, and other subjects), 1963-64, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 678)
        - Maugham family (Canterbury and Lewes), 1963-65, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 679-680)
        - Maugham family (family trees), 1962-63, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 681)
        - Maugham family (Paris), 1963-64, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 682)
        - Maugham family (United States, Appleby, and other subjects), 1941-64, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 683-688)
        - Other correspondence, 1962-66, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 689)
        - Other notes and papers, 1964, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 690)
      - "Maughams (and Snells) in France"
        - Correspondence, 1961-66, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 691-694)
        - Notes and other papers, 1863-1964, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 695-698)
          Also stored in: Folders Shelved Flat, box 327, folder 1801
      - "Maughams in America"
        - Correspondence, 1961-63 (Box 33, Folder 699)
        - Notes and other papers, 1962-63, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 700)
      - "Maughams of Brough, Appleby &c."
        - Correspondence, 1962-63 (Box 33, Folder 701)
        - Notes and other papers, 1955-62, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 702-704)
      - "Maughams of Lincolnshire"
        - Correspondence, 1961-63, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 705)
        - Notes and other papers, 1860-1963, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 706-714)
      - "Maughams of London"
        - Correspondence, 1938-63 (Box 34, Folder 715-716)
        - Notes and other papers, 1881-1963 (Box 34, Folder 717-720)
        - Notes and other papers (Box 35, Folder 721-724)
      - "W.S.M. and His Brothers &c."
        - Correspondence, 1962-66, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 725)
        - Notes and other papers, 1866-1964, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 726-729)
      - Clippings
        By or about W. Somerset Maugham Photocopies and typed transcripts, formerly in ring binders
        - Clippings, 1891-1919 (Box 35, Folder 730-731)
        - Clippings, 1921-1939 (Box 35, Folder 732-733)
        - Clippings, 1940-1945 (Box 35, Folder 734-736)
        - Clippings, 1946-1962 (Box 36, Folder 737-740)
        - "Index and Extracts from Articles by or Regarding W. Somerset Maugham", 1891-1962 (Box 36, Folder 741-746)
        - Other articles, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 747-748)
      - Other research files
        - Maugham family tree, n.d.
        - Other clippings by W. Somerset Maugham, 1940, 1962 (Box 36, Folder 749-750)
        - Other clippings about W. Somerset Maugham, 1923-65, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 751-754)
    - MAUGHAM FAMILY PAPERS
      - Maugham, George
        - Letters from Lucy Eleanor Maugham and Emanuel Andrew, 1839-45, n.d.
          FRKF 191j
      - Maugham, Robert
        - Diary, with notes and typed transcript, 1820 Sep-Oct (Box 37, Folder 755-757)
          FRKF 191f
        - Scrapbook, 1805-66, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 758)
      - Maugham, William
        See also: Writings/ Somerset and All the Maughams /Background materials, box 30, folders 656-661
        - Bickham, George. The Moral Penman...: manuscript copy, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 759)
          FRKF 191c
        - Letters from Maugham, Theophilus, 1794-99, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 760)
          Includes letters to Maugham, William Farringdon
          FRKF 191g
        - Letters from Maugham, William Farringdon, 1790-1805 (Box 37, Folder 761)
          FRKF 191i
        - Letters from others, 1753-1802 (Box 37, Folder 762)
        - Sermons, 1765-1797 (Box 37, Folder 763-768)
        - Sermons, 1798-1800 Jul (Box 38, Folder 769-771)
        - Sermons, 1800 Aug-04 Jun (Box 38, Folder 772-780)
        - Sermons, 1804 Jul-1812 (Box 39, Folder 781-785)
          Includes undated sermons
        - Other papers, 1753-1821, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 786-788)
      - Snell, Anne Alicia
        - Letters from Snell and Charles Ormand Maugham, most to Mabel Yarde, 1874-1905, n.d.: typed transcripts (Box 39, Folder 789)
          FRKF 191h
      - Other Maugham family
        - Writings, clippings, and other documents, 1713-1964, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 790-791)
          Includes passport signed by George III, King of Great Britain
          FRKF 191o
    - SUBJECT FILES
      - Gardner-Serpollet steam car, 1962-64, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 792)
      - Portraits of W. Somerset Maugham: etching and photographs of paintings, 1946, n.d.
        FRKF 191d
        FRKF 191n
      - Other files relating to W. Somerset Maugham, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 793-795)
    - PHOTOGRAPHS
      Originally in albums Includes copies of photographs; dates are for original images
      See also: Research Files, boxes 31-35, folders 671-729
      See also: Subject Files, box 327, folders 1807-1808
      All materials: FRKF 191n
      - "Maugham Family - Early, Excluding W.S.M.", 1891, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 796-798)
      - "Maugham Family - Middle, Excluding W.S.M.", 1856-1962, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 799-802)
      - "Maugham Family - Late, Excluding W.S.M", 1889-1931, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 803-806)
      - "Villa Mauresque 1.", 1963-65, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 807-809)
      - "Villa Mauresque 2.", 1959-63, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 810-812)
      - "W. Somerset Maugham, 1885-1945", 1885-1945, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 813-817)
      - "W. Somerset Maugham, 1954-1962", 1954-62, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 818-820)
      - "W. Somerset Maugham, all 1962" (Box 41, Folder 821-822)
      - "W. Somerset Maugham, 1963-1965; also Gerald Haxton and Alan Searle", 1930-65, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 823-827)
      - "W. Somerset Maugham and His Family", 1856-1965, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 828-833)
      - "W. Somerset Maugham and His Friends", 1888-1940s (Box 41, Folder 834-837)
      - "W. Somerset Maugham and His Friends", 1950s-1965, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 838-842)
      - "W. Somerset Maugham and His Friends", 1959-63, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 843-844)
      - "Whitstable and the Old Vicarage", 1963, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 845-846)
  - Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset)
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Towne, Charles Hanson, 1924 Dec 18 (Box 42, Folder 847)
        FRKF 312
  - Maupassant, Guy de
    - WRITINGS
      - "La vocation" (short story), with illustrations by Maupassant, [ca. 1887?] (Box 42, Folder 848)
        Accompanied by letter from Casimir Woznicki to [Edouard?] Champion, 1921 May 15
        FRKF 644
  - Maximilian, Emperor of Mexico
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Ministerio de Fomento, 1865 Aug 12 (Box 42, Folder 849)
        FRKF 338
      - Rosenthal, Dr., 1866 Apr 26 (Box 42, Folder 850)
        FRKF 488
    - OTHER PAPERS
      - Document conferring the imperial order of Guadalupe, 1866 Jul 6
        FRKF 337
  - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Buxton, E., 1843, 1844
        Includes quotation from Ein Sommernachtstraum
        FRKF 397
        FRKF 1141
      - Hensel, Fanny Mendelssohn, 1840 Nov 14 (Box 42, Folder 851)
        FRKF 1081
      - Kistner, Carl Friedrich, 1844 Nov 15 (Box 42, Folder 852)
        FRKF 1152
      - N. Simrock, 1838 Jan 2 (Box 42, Folder 853)
        FRKF 1082
      - Novello, J. Alfred, 1846 Feb 13 (Box 42, Folder 854)
        FRKF 229
      - Simrock
        See: N. Simrock, box 42, folder 853
      - Unidentified, 1832 Sep 5
        FRKF 386
    - MUSIC
      - Abschied (song)
        See: Gesänge, op. 19a. Winterlied, box 327, folder 1813
      - Auf Wiedersehen (song)
        - Score, 1840 Jan 22 (Box 42, Folder 855)
          Accompanied by locks of hair of Mendelssohn-Bartholdy and Cécile Jeanrenaud Mendelssohn, and by a leaf from Mendelssohn-Bartholdy's grave
          FRKF 819
      - Concerto, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 40, D minor
      - Piano part
        Inscribed by J. Alfred Novello
        FRKF 1308
      - Gesänge, op. 19a. Gruss
      - Gesänge, op. 19a. Winterlied
        Score
        With Gesänge, op. 19a. Gruss and Abschied (song), scores
        FRKF 1303
      - Lieder ohne Worte, piano, op. 85, Nr. 5
        - Music for piano, 1847 May 6
          FRKF 331
      - Motets, women's voices, organ, op. 39. Laudate pueri
        - Score, [1830]
          FRKF 332
      - Odipus in Kolonos (incidental music)
        - "Zur rossprangenden Flur," chorus: short score in copyist's manuscript, annotated by Mendelssohn-Bartholdy
          Unidentified work titled "Styrian Air" appended, written in an unidentified hand
          FRKF 771
      - Ein Sommernachtstraum (incidental music)
        See: Correspondence/Buxton, E., box 327, folder 1810
      - Verleih' uns Frieden (chorus and orchestra)
        - Version for chorus and piano: score, partly in holograph
          Accompanied by a receipt for purchase by a former owner and an English translation of the text, written in an unidentified hand
          FRKF 242
      - Unidentified
        See: Odipus in Kolonos, box 152, folder 1494
        See: Drawings/Album leaf, box 42, folder 856
    - DRAWINGS
      - Album leaf with drawing and unidentified music quotation, 1842 Sep 29 (Box 42, Folder 856)
        FRKF 1302
      - Album of drawings relating to Mendelssohn-Bartholdy's tour of Scotland in 1829, [1846 or 1847]
        FRKF 294
  - Menotti, Gian Carlo
    - MUSIC
      - Canti della lontananza
        - Dorme Pegaso: score, [ca. 1967]
          FRKF 11
  - Meredith, William
    Papers relate to James Ingram Merrill
    All materials: FRKF 676
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Boyd, Julian P. (Julian Parks) (to Meredith), 1948, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 857)
      - Merrill, Charles (to Meredith), 1950 Sep-Nov (Box 42, Folder 858)
      - Merrill, James Ingram (to Meredith), [1947]-81, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 859-863)
        Includes poems by Merrill Includes letter with postscript by David Jackson
      - Plummer, Hellen Ingram Merrill (to Meredith), n.d. (Box 43, Folder 864)
      - -----, "Tony" (to Meredith), 1948 Jun-Nov (Box 43, Folder 865)
      - Other correspondents (to Meredith), 1948, 1958 (Box 43, Folder 866)
      - Unidentified (from Merrill), n.y. Feb 1 (Box 43, Folder 867)